A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, SG 1.1, Series 300 Latin America - Series 833 Lebanon FA386b
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Java, 1915-1953; 655; 0.8 Cubic Feet; 2 __Boxes __0.8 cubic feet
  655 J Public health demonstrations, local health units
  655 L Public health education (schools of hygiene and public health)
  - Java - Medical Sciences, 655.A
    - Batavia Medical School - Bonne, Cornelius - (Pathology), 1932-1934 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Batavia Medical School - De Waart, A. - (Medical Education, Travel Grant), 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - JAV-1 "Medical Education in Java", 1915, 1923-1926, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Java - Public Health Demonstrations, 655.J
    - (Public Health Demonstrations), 1932-1939 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations), 1932-1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Batavia Medical School - Training Area, 1934-1939, 1941, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Java - Public Health Education, 655.L
    - (Public Health Education), 1928-1941, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - (Public Health Education), 1928-1941, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - (Public Health Education), 1928-1941, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - (Public Health Education), 1928-1941, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - (Public Health Education), 1928-1941, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Surinam, 1929-1949; 659; 0.2 Cubic Feet; 1 __Box __0.2 cubic feet
  - FOX-1 Fox, Leon A. "Sanitary Survey of Dutch Guiana", 1941 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Health, 1929, 1931-1932, 1939, 1941, 1943-1944, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Europe, 1920-1963; 700; 10.2 Cubic Feet; 23 __Boxes __10.2 cubic feet
  This material deals with The Rockefeller Foundation's activities in Europe and is concentrated in the 1940's. It includes 12 boxes of the Rockefeller Foundation's Health Commission records (1933-1956). There is also information concerned with the organization of The Rockefeller Foundation offices in Europe (1923-1963).
  700 (no program letter; general material which does not fit into a particular program area)
  700 A Medical sciences (research conducted in medical schools or medical research institutes, research directly applicable to the mental and physical health of human beings)
  700 C Nursing (nursing education, public health nursing)
  700 D Natural sciences and agriculture (research usually conducted in departments outside of medical schools, research in pure science, veterinary medicine or agriculture)
  700 I Malaria
  700 L Public health education (schools of hygiene and public health)
  700 R Humanities and arts
  700 S Social sciences
  - Administration - Inventory, 1942-1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Administration - Office Space, 1923-1929, 1933, 1935-1937, 1939-1942, 1944-1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Administration - Office Space, 1923-1929, 1933, 1935-1937, 1939-1942, 1944-1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Administration - Office Space, 1923-1929, 1933, 1935-1937, 1939-1942, 1944-1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Administration - Office Space, 1923-1929, 1933, 1935-1937, 1939-1942, 1944-1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Administration - Office Space, 1923-1929, 1933, 1935-1937, 1939-1942, 1944-1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Administration - Office Space, 1923-1929, 1933, 1935-1937, 1939-1942, 1944-1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Administration - Office Space, 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Administration - Office Space, 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Administration - Office Space, 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Administration - Organization, 1925, 1929, 1936, 1939-1940, 1942, 1944-1949, 1951, 1954-1955, 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Administration - Organization, 1925, 1929, 1936, 1939-1940, 1942, 1944-1949, 1951, 1954-1955, 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Economics Seminars - Alpbach Seminar, 1948-1950, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Economics Seminars - Haberler, Gottfried, 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Economics Seminars - Hayek, F. A., 1946-1948, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Economics Seminars - Morgenstern, Oskar, 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - European Business Cycle Conferences, 1933, 1935-1939 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - LEA-1 Leathers, Waller S. "Observations of Public Health in Switzerland, Belgium, England, France, Denmark, Norway and Holland", 1928 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Appropriations, 1940-1949 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Appropriations, 1940-1949 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission, May 1940-February 1941 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission, May 1940-February 1941 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission, May 1940-February 1941 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission, May 1940-February 1941 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission, March 1941-1949 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission, March 1941-1949 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission, March 1941-1949 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - RFHC DIARY, 1940-1941 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - RFHC DIARY, 1942-1946 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - RFHC DIARY, 1942-1946 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Reports - Volumes I-III - RFHC REP-1, 1940-1943; 1 Item (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Report - RFHC REP-2, 1943-1944; 1 Item (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Report - RFHC REP-3, 1946-1947; 2 Copies (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - (British Isles) - Reports - RFHC (British Isles), 1941-1943; 2 Items (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - England - Health, 1940-1944, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - England - Health, 1940-1944, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - France - Health, 1933, 1936, 1938, 1940-September 1941 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - France - Health, 1933, 1936, 1938, 1940-September 1941 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - France - Health, 1933, 1936, 1938, 1940-September 1941 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - France - Health, October 1941-1947, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - France - Health, October 1941-1947, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - France - Health, October 1941-1947, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - France - Health - Reports, 1941; 21 Items (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - France - Health - Reports, 1941; 21 Items (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - France - Health - Reports, 1941; 21 Items (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - France - Health - Reports, 1941-1945; 10 Items and Attachments (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - France - Health - Reports, 1941-1945; 10 Items and Attachments (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Influenza - England, 1940-1944 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Influenza - England, 1940-1944 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Journals, 1944-1947 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Journals, 1944-1947 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Journals, 1944-1947 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Journals, 1948-1954 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Journals, 1948-1954 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - London Office - Report, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Malaria - India, 1942-1943 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Malaria Drug Study - Peru, 1944-1948 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Malaria Drug Study - Peru, 1944-1948 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Nutrition, 1941-1944 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Nutrition - England, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Nutrition - England, 1942-1947, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Nutrition - England, 1942-1947, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Nutrition - England - Reports, 1942-1945; 15 Items (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Nutrition - England - Reports, 1942-1945; 15 Items (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Nutrition - England - Reports, 1942-1945; 15 Items (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Nutrition - Spain, 1940-1944 (Box 11, Folder 66)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Nutrition - Spain, 1940-1944 (Box 11, Folder 67)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Nutrition - Spain, 1940-1944 (Box 11, Folder 68)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Nutrition - Spain - Reports, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 69)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - O'Brien - Diary, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 70)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel, 1940-1946 (Box 11, Folder 71)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel, 1940-1946 (Box 11, Folder 72)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Balfour, M. C., 1941 (Box 11, Folder 73)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Davis, W. A., 1942 (Box 11, Folder 74)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Hudson, N. Paul, 1940-1941 (Box 11, Folder 75)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Hudson, N. Paul, 1940-1941 (Box 11, Folder 76)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Janney, John H., 1940-1941 (Box 12, Folder 77)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Markham, Floyd M., 1943-1946 (Box 12, Folder 78)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Meiklejohn, Arnold Peter, 1941-1946 (Box 12, Folder 79)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Meiklejohn, Arnold Peter, 1941-1946 (Box 12, Folder 80)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Meiklejohn, Arnold Peter, 1941-1946 (Box 12, Folder 81)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Meiklejohn, Arnold Peter, 1941-1946 (Box 12, Folder 82)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Meiklejohn, Arnold Peter, 1941-1946 (Box 12, Folder 83)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - O'Brien, Daniel F., 1940-1941 (Box 12, Folder 84)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Riehl, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 85)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Robinson, William D., 1941 (Box 12, Folder 86)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Sawyer, Wilbur Augustus, 1940-1941 (Box 12, Folder 87)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Schwentker, Francis F., 1940-1942 (Box 12, Folder 88)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Smith, Hugh H., 1940-1944 (Box 12, Folder 89)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Snyder, John C., 1941-1942 (Box 13, Folder 90)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Stevenson, Stuart S., 1943-1946 (Box 13, Folder 91)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Strode, George K., 1940-1941 (Box 13, Folder 92)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Stuart, Harold Coe, 1940-1943 (Box 13, Folder 93)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Sydenstricker, Virgil Preston, 1941-1944 (Box 13, Folder 94)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Warren, A. J., 1940 (Box 13, Folder 95)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Wheeler, C. M., 1942 (Box 13, Folder 96)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Wright, D. E., 1940-1941 (Box 13, Folder 97)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Personnel - Youmans, John B., 1940-1942 (Box 13, Folder 98)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Russia, 1941-1943 (Box 14, Folder 99)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Russia, 1941-1943 (Box 14, Folder 100)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Typhus Fever - Spain, 1940-1942 (Box 14, Folder 101)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission - Typhus Fever - Spain, 1940-1942 (Box 14, Folder 102)
  - Rockefeller Special Relief Fund, 1923, 1926-1928, 1932 (Box 14, Folder 103)
  - War - (General), May 1939-October 1939 (Box 14, Folder 104)
  - War - (General), May 1939-October 1939 (Box 14, Folder 105)
  - War - (General), May 1939-October 1939 (Box 14, Folder 106)
  - War - (General), November 1939-1942 (Box 15, Folder 107)
  - War - (General), November 1939-1942 (Box 15, Folder 108)
  - War - (General), November 1939-1942 (Box 15, Folder 109)
  - War - (General), November 1939-1942 (Box 15, Folder 110)
  - War - Humanities, 1939-1940 (Box 15, Folder 111)
  - War - I. H. D., 1939-1940, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 112)
  - War - Medical Sciences, 1939-1940 (Box 15, Folder 113)
  - War - Natural Sciences, 1939-1940 (Box 15, Folder 114)
  - War - Social Sciences, 1939-1940, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 115)
  - Europe - Medical Sciences, 700.A
    This material deals with The Rockefeller Foundation's activities in Europe and is concentrated in the 1940's. It includes 12 boxes of the Rockefeller Foundation's Health Commission records (1933-1956). There is also information concerned with the organization of The Rockefeller Foundation officess in Europe (1923-1963).
    - (Medical Sciences), 1922-1930, 1932 (Box 16, Folder 116)
    - (Medical Sciences), 1922-1930, 1932 (Box 16, Folder 117)
    - (Medical Sciences) - Reports, 1926-1931; 6 Items (Box 16, Folder 118)
    - Developmental Aid, 1925-1934 (Box 16, Folder 119)
    - Emergency Aid - (Appropriations), 1920-1927 (Box 16, Folder 120)
    - Emergency Aid, 1919-1922 (Box 16, Folder 121)
    - Emergency Aid, 1919-1922 (Box 16, Folder 122)
    - Emergency Aid, 1923-1926 (Box 17, Folder 123)
    - Emergency Aid, 1923-1926 (Box 17, Folder 124)
    - EV Eversole, Henry "Europe - Medical Education - Journal.. .", 1923-1926 (Box 17, Folder 125)
    - Medical Literature Aid, 1920-1927, 1929, 1931-1932, 1950-1951 (Box 17, Folder 126)
    - Medical Literature Aid, 1920-1927, 1929, 1931-1932, 1950-1951 (Box 17, Folder 127)
    - Medical Literature Aid, 1920-1927, 1929, 1931-1932, 1950-1951 (Box 17, Folder 128)
    - Medical Literature Aid, 1920-1927, 1929, 1931-1932, 1950-1951 (Box 17, Folder 129)
    - Neurophysiology Study - (Gerard, R. Waldo), 1933-1937 (Box 18, Folder 130)
    - Neurophysiology Study - (Gerard, R. Waldo) - Report - NEU, 1934-1935 (Box 18, Folder 131)
    - Research Aid Fund, 1929-1940, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 132)
    - Research Aid Fund, 1929-1940, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 133)
    - Struthers, Rolf R., 1947-1951 (Box 19, Folder 134)
    - Struthers, Rolf R., 1947-1951 (Box 19, Folder 135)
    - Struthers, Rolf R., 1947-1951 (Box 19, Folder 136)
  - Europe - Nursing, 700.C
    - (Nursing), 1920-1925 (Box 19, Folder 137)
    - (Nursing), 1920-1925 (Box 19, Folder 138)
    - (Nursing), 1920-1925 (Box 19, Folder 139)
    - (Nursing), 1926-1930, 1932, 1947-1949 (Box 20, Folder 140)
    - (Nursing), 1926-1930, 1932, 1947-1949 (Box 20, Folder 141)
    - (Nursing), 1926-1930, 1932, 1947-1949 (Box 20, Folder 142)
    - (Nursing), 1926-1930, 1932, 1947-1949 (Box 20, Folder 143)
    - (Nursing) - Reports, 1923-1931; 12 Items (Box 20, Folder 144)
    - Emergency Aid, 1931-1933, 1935-1938 (Box 20, Folder 145)
    - League of Red Cross Societies, 1921-1926 (Box 20, Folder 146)
  - Europe - Natural Sciences and Agriculture, 700.D
    - (Natural Sciences and Agriculture), 1932-1933, 1939-1940, 1945-1948, 1950, 1955 (Box 20, Folder 147)
    - (Natural Sciences and Agriculture), 1932-1933, 1939-1940, 1945-1948, 1950, 1955 (Box 20, Folder 148)
    - (Natural Sciences and Agriculture) - Reports, 1945-1954; 2 Items (Box 20, Folder 149)
    - Danzig Technical High School - Chemistry - (Butenandt A.), 1932-1939 (Box 21, Folder 150)
    - European Scientists - (Visits), 1949-1950 (Box 21, Folder 151)
    - HER-1 Herrick, C. Judson "Report of Inquiries into Teaching and Research in the Biological Science in Great Britain, The Netherlands, and Belgium", 1926-1927 (Box 21, Folder 152)
    - Human Biology - Herrick, C. Judson - (Visits), 1926 (Box 21, Folder 153)
    - Research Aid Fund, 1929-1940, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 154)
    - Research Aid Fund, 1929-1940, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 155)
    - Research Aid Fund, 1929-1940, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 156)
    - Research Aid Fund - Report, 1932-1934; 5 Items (Box 21, Folder 157)
  - Europe - Malaria, 700.I
    - Eastern Mediterranean Anopheline Survey, 1936 (Box 21, Folder 158)
  - Europe - Public Health Education, 700.L
    - Developmental Aid - Institutes of Hygiene, 1939-1941, 1944, 1946 (Box 22, Folder 159)
    - Travel Fund for Health Officials, 1928-1935 (Box 22, Folder 160)
  - Europe - Humanities and Arts, 700.R
    - (Humanities), 1929-1930, 1933-1934, 1938-1939, 1943-1945, 1947, 1949-1950, 1952-1958, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 161)
    - (Humanities), 1929-1930, 1933-1934, 1938-1939, 1943-1945, 1947, 1949-1950, 1952-1958, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 162)
    - Humanities Program - No. I, II, 1934-1950 (Box 22, Folder 0162A)
    - Humanities Program - No. I, II, 1934-1950 (Box 22, Folder 0162B)
    - Report on Libraries, Microphotography, Motion Pictures and Radio - Marshall, John - MAR-1, 1938 (Box 022A, Folder 0162C)
    - MAR-2 "Opportunities in the Humanities in Europe" Report on Visit by John Marshall, October 1944-February 1945 (Box 022A, Folder 162)
    - MAR-3 "Opportunities in the Humanities in Europe" Report on Visit by John Marshall, October 1945-November 1945 (Box 022A, Folder 0162E)
    - Research Aid, 1930-1935, 1939-1940 (Box 022A, Folder 163)
    - Report on Libraries, Microphotography, Motion Pictures and Radio - Marshall, John - MAR-1, 1938 (Box 022A, Folder 0162C)
    - MAR-2 "Opportunities in the Humanities in Europe" Report on Visit by John Marshall, October 1944-February 1945 (Box 022A, Folder 162)
    - MAR-3 "Opportunities in the Humanities in Europe" Report on Visit by John Marshall, October 1945-November 1945 (Box 022A, Folder 0162E)
    - Research Aid, 1930-1935, 1939-1940 (Box 022A, Folder 163)
  - Europe - Social Sciences, 700.S
    - (Social Sciences), 1928-1941 (Box 022A, Folder 164)
    - (Social Sciences), 1928-1941 (Box 022A, Folder 165)
    - (Social Sciences), 1928-1941 (Box 022A, Folder 166)
    - (Social Sciences), 1944-1945 (Box 23, Folder 167)
    - (Social Sciences) - Reports, 1946; 2 Copies (Box 23, Folder 168)
    - Crane, Robert Treat - (Visit), 1946-1948 (Box 23, Folder 169)
    - Crane, Robert Treat - Reports - CRA-1, CRA-2, 1946-1947; 4 Copies (Box 23, Folder 170)
    - Research Aid Fund, 1930-1940 (Box 23, Folder 171)
    - Research Aid Fund, 1930-1940 (Box 23, Folder 172)
    - WAL Walker, Sydnor H. "Social Welfare and Public Administration in Europe", 1928 (Box 23, Folder 173)
- Eurasia, 1930; 702; 0.5 Cubic Feet; 1 __Box __0.5 cubic feet
  702 I Malaria
  - Eurasia - Malaria, 1930; 702.I; 0.5 Cubic Feet; 1 __Box __0.5 cubic feet
    - (Malaria), 1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Albania, 1924-1951; 704; 0.5 Cubic Feet; 2 __Boxes __0.5 cubic feet
  The concentration of this material is in the Rockefeller Foundation's support of research in Malaria (1924-1943) with a report by Lewis W. Hackett on the subject in 1926.
  The 704 series is divided into the following three subseries:
  704 (no program letter; general material which does not fit into a particular program area)
  704 I Malaria
  704 J Public health demonstrations, local health units
  - Health, 1931-1932, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Relief (No RF Appropriation), 1924 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Albania - Malaria, 704.I
    - (Malaria) - (Appropriations), 1924-1931 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - (Malaria), 1924-1926, 1928-1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - (Malaria), 1924-1926, 1928-1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - (Malaria), 1924-1926, 1928-1943 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - (Malaria), 1924-1926, 1928-1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - (Malaria) - Reports, 1929-1939, 1942; 4 Items (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - (Malaria) - Supplementary Material, 1929-1939 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - HAC-2 Hackett, Lewis W. "Albania and its Malaria Problem", 1926 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Albania - Public Health Demonstrations, 704.J
    - Tirana Health Center - (Appropriations), 1935-1940 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Tirana Health Center, 1935-1941 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Austria, 1921-1951; 705; 2 Cubic Feet; 5 __Boxes __2 cubic feet
  Material in this series is concentrated in three subject areas; medical science (1929-1951), natural science (1930-1950), and social science (1930-1951). Also included is a report on Nursing by F. Elisabeth Crowell.
  The material is divided into the following nine subseries:
  705 (no program letter; general material which does not fit into a particular program area)
  705 A Medical sciences (research conducted in medical schools or medical research institutes, research directly applicable to the mental and physical health of human beings)
  705 C Nursing (nursing education, public health nursing)
  705 D Natural sciences and agriculture (research usually conducted in departments outside of medical schools, research in pure science, veterinary medicine or agriculture)
  705 E Fellowships, scholarships, training awards
  705 J Public health demonstrations, local health units
  705 R Humanities and arts
  705 S Social sciences
  705 T Tuberculosis
  - BEV Bevier, George "Public Health in Austria", 1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Styria - (Epidemiology and Rural Health Work), 1930-1935 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - University of Vienna - Hygienic Institute, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Austria - Medical Sciences, 705.A
    - Emergency Aid, 1921-1926 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Emergency Aid, 1921-1926 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Gesellschaft Der Aerzte - (Medical Literature), 1921-1933 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - PEA Pearce, Richard M. "Medical Education in Austria", 1922 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - University of Graz - Chemistry - (Soltys, Arnulf), 1931, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - University of Graz - Physiology - (Wagner, Richard), 1929 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - University of Vienna - Chiari, Herman - (Pathology), 1947 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - University of Vienna - First Medical Clinic - (Eppinger, Hans; Mark, Hermann), 1933-1935 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - University of Vienna - Fuchsig, Paul - (Surgery, Travel Grant), 1948-1951 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - University of Vienna - Neuropathology, 1935, 1938, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - University of Vienna - Obstetrics - (Kraul, Ludwig), 1930 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Vienna Heart Station, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Vienna Municipal Hospital - (Neurological Clinic; Schonbauer, Leopold), 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Austria - Nursing, 705.C
    - (Nursing), 1922-1927, 1931-1932 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - CRO-1 Crowell, F. Elisabeth "Memorandum: Study of Sick Nursing and Health Visiting", 1923 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Austria - Natural Sciences and Agriculture, 705.D
    - Technical High School, Graz - Physics - (Kohlrausch, K. W. F.), 1933-1939, 1946-1949 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - University of Innsbruck - Radiation - (Hess, Victor F.), 1932-1935 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - University of Vienna - Chemistry - (Pollack, J.), 1932 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - University of Vienna - First Institute of Physics - (Mattaugh, J.), 1930 (Box 3, Folder 22)